Mss.Rec.192 Mss.Rec.192
American Philosophical Society
Recordings of Yuchi people in Oklahoma
1994
Mss.Rec.192
American Philosophical Society
12.0 Tape(s)
The collection includes English interviews with multiple Yuchi Indians on various topics, such as genealogy, Yuchi history, relations with the U.S. government, hunting and fishing, local churches, and tribal government. One tape records a Yuchi language class and planning meeting with numerous informal conversations. This collection also includes recordings of Green Corn Dance, Polecat Arbor Dance, Evening Dances, Ribbon Dance, and other performances. Recorded by Pamela Wallace at Kellyville, Sapulpa, Coweta, Glencoe, and Hectorville, Oklahoma in June and July of 1994.
12 sound cassettes (8 hr., 20 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Cawhee, Bill
Cawhee, Mose
Squire, Martha
Wallace, Pamela S.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Pamela Wallace in 1994 (Acc. 1994-1080r). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
A project report on these field recordings is available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Churches--Oklahoma; Sound recordings; Yuchi dance; Yuchi Indians--Ethnic identity; Yuchi Indians--Genealogy; Yuchi Indians--Government relations; Yuchi Indians--History; Yuchi Indians--Music; Yuchi Indians--Politics and government; Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs; Yuchi language
- Audio recordings
  - Interview with Bill Cahwee [1 of 3], 1994-06-27; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:21; Cawhee, Bill; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Glencoe (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Claims; Yuchi Indians--Government relations; Yuchi Indians--History; Yuchi Indians--Politics and government
  - Interview with Bill Cahwee [2 of 3], 1994-06-27; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:25; Cawhee, Bill; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Glencoe (Okla.); Oklahoma--History; Yuchi Indians--Genealogy; Yuchi Indians--History
  - Interview with Bill Cahwee [3 of 3], 1994-06-27; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:33; Cawhee, Bill; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Glencoe (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Ethnic identity; Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs; Yuchi language
  - Interview with Mose Cahwee [1 of 2], 1994-06-29; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:30; Cawhee, Mose; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Deer hunting; Fishing; Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Genealogy; Yuchi Indians--History; Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs
  - Interview with Mose Cahwee [2 of 2], 1994-06-29; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:25; Cawhee, Mose; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Ethnic identity; Yuchi Indians--Social conditions; Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs; Yuchi language
  - Interview with Martha Squire [1 of 2], 1994-06-29; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:26; Squire, Martha; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Coweta (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Genealogy
  - Interview with Martha Squire [2 of 2], 1994-06-29; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:42; Squire, Martha; Wallace, Pamela S.
  - Yuchi Language Class [1 of 2], 1994-06-29; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:42; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Scope and Contents note
    In English only. Excerpts of a planning meeting and miscellaneous informal conversations. Subsequent program contains some Yuchi.
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs; Yuchi language--Study and teaching
  - Yuchi Language Class [2 of 2], 1994-06-29; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:27; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Consists of excerpts from a Yuchi language class and miscellaneous informal conversations.
  - Green Corn at Duck Creek [1 of 2], 1994-06-24; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:43; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Program is mostly silent from 1:42 to 3:26.
    Hectorville (Okla.); Yuchi dance; Yuchi Indians--Music; Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs
  - Green Corn at Duck Creek [2 of 2], 1994-06-24; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:30; Wallace, Pamela S.
  - Polecat Arbor Dance [1 of 2], 1994-07-01; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:33; Wallace, Pamela S.
    Kellyville (Okla.); Yuchi dance; Yuchi Indians--Music; Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs
  - Polecat Arbor Dance [2 of 2], 1994-07-01; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:06; Wallace, Pamela S.
  - Conversation on genealogy, 1994-07; 07-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:04; Wallace, Pamela S.
    A nearby, background conversation is audible through most of the program.
    Oklahoma; Yuchi Indians--Genealogy
  - Polecat Lizard Dance, Plus Evening Dances [1 of 2], 1994-07-08; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:27; Wallace, Pamela S.
    The date of the recording is given as 1994-07-07 during the recording itself, but is labeled as 1994-07-08.
  - Polecat Lizard Dance, Plus Evening Dances [2 of 2], 1994-07-08; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:24; Wallace, Pamela S.
  - Polecat Evening Dances, 1994-07-08; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:07; Wallace, Pamela S.
  - Polecat Green Corn Dance, 1994-07-09; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:40; Wallace, Pamela S.
    The program is only faintly audible from 0:17 to 2:40. It is identical to APSdigrec_2484, identified as "Polecat - Following Ribbon Dance."
  - Polecat Green Corn Dance, Final Men's Dance [1 of 2], 1994-07-09; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:28; Wallace, Pamela S.
  - Polecat Green Corn Dance, Final Men's Dance [2 of 2], 1994-07-09; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:09; Wallace, Pamela S.
  - Polecat Ribbon Dance, 1994-07-09; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:40; Wallace, Pamela S.
    The program is only faintly audible from 0:17 to 2:40. It is identical to APSdigrec_2481, identified as "Polecat Green Corn Dance."